(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention / ご来場の皆様へ
Attention / To all attendees
演出の都合上、照明の明滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK.
受注生産グッズ ①
Made-to-order Goods 1
受注生産グッズ ②
Made-to-order Goods 2
受注生産グッズ ③
Made-to-order Goods 3
ライブグッズ販売開始
Live Goods Sales Start
Spectra of Nova Message Board
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: To all visitors
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering (loudly) is OK.
受注生産グッズ①
Made-to-order goods 1
ライブグッズ販売開始
Live goods sales start
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
SPONSORS 協賛
SPONSORS
最近行ったのよ カラオケ。
I went to karaoke recently.
なんさ、2時間で解散と思うじゃん。
You think it's over after two hours, right?
そっからなのよ。
But that's when it starts.
え？
What?
いろんなこと出来るわけ。
You can do all sorts of things.
ヤバいぞ、美味い！
It's crazy, amazing!
PLAY! NEW(X). X PARK
X PARK最高！
X PARK is the best!
JOYSOUND X1
明太子をつくってよかった。 博多中洲 ふくや
I'm glad I made mentaiko. Hakata Nakasu Fukuya
ふくや！
Fukuya!
明太子がー！
Mentaiko is!
キレコ！
Kireco!
マコ！
Mako!
明太子が生まれ変わる新しい技を編み出しました。
We've come up with a new technique for mentaiko to be reborn.
行きます！
Here we go!
ふくやの明太子から生まれたメンチーズシリーズ。
The Men Cheese series, born from Fukuya's mentaiko.
ピリリな味わい、マコも大好き。
A spicy flavor, Mako loves it too.
詳しくはWebで！
Check the website for details!
My name is Charity Powers,
and I sing for Sony's 'Jazz' project.
When you found us, you created quite a problem for us to solve.
And this song turned out much better than anything else I've ever made.
It's called 'Spectra of Nova'!
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Please wait a moment until the performance begins.
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
For production reasons, please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK
Vocal cheering is permitted.
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: To all attendees
受注生産グッズ
Made-to-order Goods
ライブグッズ販売開始
Live goods sales start
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK.
受注生産グッズ
Made-to-order merchandise
ライブグッズ販売開始
Live goods sales start
本日は、星街すいせいライブツアー2024『Spectra of Nova』にご来場いただき、ありがとうございます。
Thank you for coming to Hoshimachi Suisei Live Tour 2024 "Spectra of Nova" today.
星街すいせいです！
I'm Hoshimachi Suisei!
皆さん！ 最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために、
Everyone! In order for you to enjoy the live to the end,
いくつかご案内させていただきますので、よく聞いておいてくださいね！
I have a few announcements, so please listen carefully!
公演中の撮影、録音、録画機材の使用は固くお断りいたします。
Photography, recording, and the use of recording equipment during the performance are strictly prohibited.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は、無理をせず近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
If by any chance you feel unwell, please do not push yourself and inform a nearby staff member.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、ステージに物を投げ込むなど、
Mosh pits, diving, and throwing objects onto the stage,
他の皆の迷惑になったり公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です。
or any other actions that cause trouble for others or interfere with the performance, are strictly prohibited.
ルールを守って盛り上がってくださいね！
Please follow the rules and have a great time!
はーい？
Ready?
いい返事！
Good response!
また、本公演は映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席が映り込む場合がございます。
Also, for this performance, video streaming and photography cameras are in the venue, and there may be shots of the audience.
これらの映像や写真はプロモーションなどに使用される可能性がございますので、あらかじめご了承ください。
These videos and photos may be used for promotion, so please understand this in advance.
また、ライブのハッシュタグは「#駆け抜ける星街」です。
Also, the live hashtag is "#駆け抜ける星街".
ハッシュタグを使ってたくさん盛り上げてください！
Please use the hashtag to get everyone excited!
それでは…
And now...
それでは、開演までもうあと少し！
Well then, it's just a little longer until the show starts!
ドキドキしてきたね、みんな！
You're getting excited, aren't you, everyone?!
皆で一緒に盛り上がりましょう！
Let's all get excited together!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
行くぞー、さいたまー！！
Let's go, Saitama!!
Are you ready?
ビビデバ
Bibideba
Hoshimachi Suisei Live Tour 2024 SPECTRA of NOVA
雲も土埃も 駆け引き上手な大人
Clouds and dust clouds, adults who are good at bargaining
だめね そんな言葉 信用できない
It's no good, I can't trust such words
手垢で書いてきて 進化し続けるテクノロジー
Written with fingerprints, technology that continues to evolve
伝えて 人肌の温もり
Tell me, the warmth of human skin
ねぇ このままずっと 降り止まない雨の世界だ
Hey, like this forever, it's a world of never-ending rain
もう 悲しくない 人は慣れる生き物だから
I'm not sad anymore, because people are creatures of habit
そう 白紙になった 青春の何ページ目だったっけ
Yeah, it became a blank page, what page of youth was it again?
今 君に会いたいと 涙流して
Now, wanting to see you, I'm shedding tears
...あげてる
...screaming.
ふんばり けったり 注意散漫人生の点呼
Struggling and kicking, a roll call of a distracted life.
新しい 時代を乗りこなしていくんだ
I'm going to ride out this new era.
透明で 鮮明で 叫び声あげてる
Transparent, vivid, and letting out a scream.
前のめり つのり 失敗しては学んでいく
Leaning forward, intensifying, learning from every failure.
もうこのままずっと降り止まない雨の世界だ
It's a world of rain that won't stop falling like this anymore.
愛するしかない それしかない 器用じゃないから
I have no choice but to love, that's all I have, because I'm not clumsy.
そう白紙になった青春の何ページ目だったっけ
Yeah, which page of my youth that turned into a blank sheet was it?
忘れ物思い出せないまま 忘れそう
Unable to remember what I've forgotten, I feel like I'll forget it all.
このままじゃ...
At this rate...
青空の形 見えない 見えないよ あなたが
I can't see the shape of the blue sky, I can't see it, or you.
あなただって同じ じっとなんてしてられない
You're the same, you can't just stand still.
動き出すよ この身かけて こぼさないよ
I'm starting to move, risking this body, I won't let it spill.
泣いたってしょうがないさ
It's no use crying anyway.
ねえこのままずっと降り止まない雨の世界だ
Hey, it's a world of rain that won't stop falling like this.
もう悲しくない 人はなれる生き物だから
I'm not sad anymore, because humans are creatures that can adapt.
そう白紙になった青春の何ページ目だったっけ
Yeah, which page of my youth that turned into a blank sheet was it?
今君に会いたいと涙こらえて
Now, holding back tears as I want to see you.
サヨナラだ サヨナラだって 認めたくないけど
It's goodbye, even if I don't want to admit it's goodbye.
雨上がりのこの世界が 眩しいから
Because this world after the rain is so bright.
もう帰らない 振り返らない 思い出とともに
I won't go back, I won't look back, along with the memories.
新しい風にあおられ そしてまた
Buffeted by a new wind, and then again...
君に会いたいと願い
...wishing to see you.
駆けてゆく
I'll run on.
もっちょっぴっ 乙に合いますか 甘ったるいだけじゃ満足しないで
Just a little bit more, does it suit your taste? Don't be satisfied with just sweetness.
さあ回って首できてんの?
Now spin around, is your neck ready?
じゃ Time is up Time is up
Then, time is up, time is up!
いくぞ埼玉! Ready? One, two, three!
Let's go, Saitama! Ready? One, two, three!
めめめめでこんな後先と 右往左往しても人間だっか
Even if I'm confused about the consequences, back and forth, I'm still human, right?
そう一辺倒しても体勢OK 明日もセオリー
Even if I'm single-minded, my posture is OK, tomorrow is also a theory.
ああもう鬱陶しい ノイズさらっていい夢 聞いたことない爆音で
Ah, it's so annoying, sweep away the noise for a good dream with a roar you've never heard.
チリみたいな誇りっぽいの 急いで手放したいね
I want to hurry up and let go of this dust-like pride.
不条理な善よりもでかいのくれ 私にステージをくれ
Give me something bigger than absurd goodness, give me a stage.
Let's get up Step into the place
好きに踊りたいんだ
I want to dance however I like.
特権階級なんて大層なこと言ってないの 的、射て 的、射して
I'm not saying anything grand like 'privileged class', just shoot the target, pierce the target.
あーは 前例ないくらいに 燃やしちゃいたいなって
Ah-ha, I want to burn it all down like never before.
狭い部屋の中だって硬い心臓に 膨張してるんだろう
Even in a small room, it's probably expanding in a hard heart.
Ah...
限界点にブーストして 順序は問うの滑稽で
Boost to the limit, it's ridiculous to ask the order.
皮肉なほどに狂うものなの 知らないな ちょっとバイバイ 狼煙を上げろ派手に
It's ironically a crazy thing, I don't know, bye-bye, raise the signal fire flamboyantly.
世界の真ん中へ
To the center of the world.
メメモリ乗り越えてベッドして 受け止め切るはずないな
Overcoming the memento mori, betting on it, there's no way I can take it all in.
共依存の際限は多分気まぐれ
The limit of codependency is probably a whim.
じゃあどんだけなんだって最高潮 Q&A ばっか
So how much is it, the climax, just Q&A.
何時 私の全身全霊を知れ
Always, know my whole heart and soul.
迷いはない 今夜 嘘が手の世界に 的、射て 的、射して あばれろ
There's no hesitation tonight, in a world of lies, shoot the target, pierce the target, run wild.
前例ないけど 燃やし尽くしちゃえば 赤くなるだけなんだから
There's no precedent, but if you burn it all down, it'll just turn red.
歴史になるんだ
It becomes history
そこに立つ私に
For me, standing there
Ah ah 不可能かもないの
Ah ah, nothing is impossible
尋常じゃなくドレスで
In an extraordinary dress
それが常識と思われても知らないんだ
I don't care if that's thought of as common sense
強引のペースで波乱は続くから
The turbulence continues at a forced pace
世界外覆せば
If I overturn the world
燃えるほど
The more it burns
弾けるほど
The more it pops
ステージは熱くなる
The stage gets hotter
だからまだ振り絞れよハニー
So give it your all, honey
ちゃんと声は届くから
Because your voice will surely reach
さいたま！
Saitama!
まだまだまだ声出せますよね！
You can still put out more voice, right!
行くぞ！
Let's go!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
あぁ 自転なくない？
Ah, isn't there no rotation?
燃やしたいなって
I want to burn it up
煙の中立って心の心臓に
Standing in the smoke, in the heart of my heart
膨張してるんだろう
It's probably expanding
Ah ah リミット数にブーストして
Ah ah, boost to the limit count!
つまり燃やし尽くせば
In other words, if you burn it all out
不可思議なくなって歴史になるんだ
The mystery disappears and it becomes history
そこに立つ私に
For me, standing there
Ah ah 不可能かもない尋常なんだよ
Ah ah, it's an extraordinary thing that might not be impossible
それで食らえんだ
Take that!
適当な理由で口挟むなよ
Don't interject with half-baked reasons
知らないならちょっと黙るか道を開けろよハニー
If you don't know, just shut up or clear the way, honey
世界もそして錯乱へ
The world then falls into confusion
燃やし尽くして！
Burn it all out!
灼熱に転生！
Reincarnate into the heat!
白いカーテンの滑る
The sliding white curtains
みたいな朝のようでまるで違う
Like the morning, but completely different
交差する細彩
Intersecting fine colors
新しく染めるテクスチャ混ぜ
Mixing in newly dyed textures
Take-offのストーリーテラー
The storyteller of take-off
迷い子は私じゃダメ？
Am I not allowed to be a lost child?
安全圏のサバイバル
Survival in the safety zone
何を信じる？ Oh oh
What do you believe? Oh oh
眩しくて逸らした初期衝動今追随して
The initial impulse I looked away from because it was too bright, I'll follow it now
空の愛の言葉ばかりで聞き飽きてきたでしょう
You're tired of hearing nothing but empty words of love, aren't you?
落流星のダンス想って退屈してんじゃない？
Thinking about the shooting star's dance, aren't you bored?
Are you ready to dance?
天災 一遇の入星
Natural disaster, a once-in-a-lifetime meteor
最小 光速のシンパシーで
Minimum, with light-speed sympathy
主観主義のイノセンス
The innocence of subjectivism
天災 一石も世界も自分次第ね
Natural disaster, a single stone and the world are all up to you
さっとの革命の狼煙は
The signal fire of a sudden revolution
覚悟、変化を恐れないで
Don't fear resolution or change
豪語さ
A boast
描いた大地を駆ける唯一の光
The only light running through the earth I drew
乾いて変えたいの連鎖が
A parched chain of wanting to change
まやかしを火種焚き付けろ
Set the deception ablaze
六千万年に一度きりのストライクスマップ
A strike-map only once in sixty million years
ミラクルにしよう エンカウント
Let's make it a miracle, encounter
空に駆けた 遠すぎる欠片
Pieces that ran to the sky, too far away
光速へ魅せられ誰も知らない
Fascinated by light speed, nobody knows
惑星が導いたレイダー
The raider guided by the planet
What do you need? What do you taste? 望む場所へと
What do you need? What do you taste? To the place you desire
Get get get get yeah!
無謀な夢なら青天井 無題呆状からハイテンション
If it's a reckless dream, sky's the limit. From blankness to high tension
キラキラ銀河の果てまで Please follow me now
To the end of the sparkling galaxy, please follow me now
収容滅花か、後ロ瞬火
Containment of the dying flower, or the subsequent flash of fire
ちょっとそれ、五感で確かめて秘め
Check that with your five senses and keep it hidden
モニター越しの輝きじゃつまんない
Brilliance through a monitor is boring
飛び出す外なるQuest to heaven
Jumping out to the outward quest to heaven
目を逸らさず見ててね
Don't look away, keep watching
夢の麗門…
The beautiful gate of dreams...
踏み出した刹那の色
The color of the moment you step out
クニュー・テーゼ Get up days
Knew thesis, get up days
希望も絶望も自分次第ね
Both hope and despair are up to you
さっとの革命の火蓋は
The start of a sudden revolution
覚悟、変化を望む表情で
Resolution, with an expression desiring change
豪語さ
A boast
描いた心に満ちた孤高の光
The solitary light that filled the heart I drew
味気ない偶然の連続が
A series of dull coincidences
迷いの光を連れてくる
Will bring a light of hesitation
六千万年に一度きりのストライクスマップ
A strike-map only once in sixty million years
ミラクルにしよう Ah ah ah
Let's make it a miracle, Ah ah ah
I'm ready to dance!
さいたまー！
Saitama—!
ういー、ちょっと、
Phew, hey,
頭３曲からブチ上がりすぎじゃないですか？
Aren't you guys way too hyped from the first three songs?
はい、ということで、彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石、
All right, as I was saying, I'm the diamond in the rough who arrived like a comet,
バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！
the virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei!
すいちゃんはー？
Sui-chan wa—?
今日もかわいいー！
Kyou mo kawaii—!
今日も声がデカい。
Your voices are loud today, too.
今日もバッチリですよ、皆さん。いいじゃないですかー。
You guys are doing perfectly today, as well. Looking good!
ということで、星街すいせいライブツアー2024、
And so, Hoshimachi Suisei Live Tour 2024,
「Spectra of Nova」、いよいよ始まりましたー！
"Spectra of Nova", has finally begun!
ちょっと待って、一回水飲む、ちょっと待って。
Wait a second, I'm gonna drink some water, hold on.
ちょっとブチ上げすぎましたよ、私も。
I got a bit too hyped myself.
いや、楽しいですね、やはりライブというものは。
Man, lives really are fun after all.
今回、初のライブツアーで、初日はさいたまスーパーアリーナ。
This is my first live tour, and the first day is at Saitama Super Arena.
デカい！
It's huge!
もうね、あんなところまであのお客さんがいて、
I mean, there are people all the way back there,
見える？私のこと見える？振って振って、見える？
Can you see? Can you see me? Wave, wave! Can you see?
あー、私も見えるよ！振って、こっちもこっちもこっちも。
Ah, I can see you too! Wave! Over here, and here, and here.
あー、見えるよ！イェーイ！
Ah, I see you! Yay!
あ、なんかめっちゃ聞こえる、「かわいい」って言った？
Oh, I can hear you loud and clear. Did you say "cute"?
今日もかわいいー！
Kyou mo kawaii—!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
さあ、皆さん聞き馴染みのない曲があったんじゃないですか？
So, wasn't there a song you weren't familiar with?
はい、昨日告知したんですけれども、
Yes, I announced it yesterday,
あの、新曲の「Awake」というものがですね、
but my new song "Awake",
出来上がりましたー！あんな感じです。
it's finished! It sounds like that.
はい、本日11月14日24時に、デジタルリリースしますので、
Yes, today, November 14th, at midnight, it will be released digitally,
1日10回は聞いてくださいね、ここにいる皆さん。
so everyone here, please listen to it at least 10 times a day.
はーい！
Yes!
そしてさらに、本日公演終了後にですね、
And what's more, after today's performance finishes,
「Awake」のMVを公開しちゃいまーす！
I'll be releasing the MV for "Awake"!
この「Awake」のMVがね、なんかすごいギャル、
The MV for "Awake" is, like, super "gyaru",
もうね、すごいギャルなの。
it's really "gyaru".
みんな見たらね、思うよ。「星街すごいギャルになった」って。
When you see it, you'll think, "Hoshimachi's become such a gyaru."
思うんで、
That's what you'll think,
かわいいよー！ギャルでもかわいいよー！
You're cute! You're cute even as a gyaru!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
じゃあ、ちょっとね、あの、スマホ持ってきていい？スマホ。
Now then, can I, uh, go grab my smartphone? My smartphone.
ちょっとここで、プレミア公開の待機所を作ろうかなって思っちゃってる。
I was thinking of setting up the premiere waitroom right here, actually.
で、ちなみにこれ確認できるのは、配信のみんなだけっていうね。
And by the way, the only ones who can check this are the stream viewers.
えー、だって会場にいるみんな今、機内モードにしてるもんね？携帯ね？
Well, I mean, everyone here at the venue has their phones in airplane mode, right?
はーい。
Right.
じゃあ、行きますよ。えっとね、こ、この上のとこなん、上の。
All right, here I go. Um, it's, like, this top part here, the top.
これでどう？え、これで、これで？
How's this? Is this, is this it?
できてる？できてるかな？
Is it working? I wonder if it's working.
わかんないよー！
We don't know!
会場にいるみんなわかんないよね。できたかな？
Everyone at the venue wouldn't know. Did it work?
ちょっと配信のコメント見るわ。
I'll check the stream comments.
うーん...来た、来た！来てる来てる！できてる！できてる！やったー！
Hmm... It's up! It's there, it's there! It's working! It's working! Yay!
あ、できてるらしいですよ、皆さん。できてるらしいですわ。
Oh, apparently it's working, everyone! It seems to be working.
え、これプレミア公開になってるんだよね？そうだよね。
Wait, it's set for a premiere, right? Yeah, it is.
できてるできてる、来た、なってるらしいわ。
It's working, it's working, it's up, it seems it is.
これがすいちゃんのスマホ、わーい。
This is Sui-chan's smartphone. Yay!
かわいいー！
So cute!
ありがとうございます. あ、ということでなくなりました。
Thank you very much. Oh, and with that, it's gone.
ちょっとね、みんなもね、帰ったら、1日100回ぐらい聞いてくださいね。
Hey guys, when you get home, please listen to it about 100 times a day.
おー！
Oh—!
お願いします。え、どうだった？ちなみに。めっちゃ良かった？
Please. Oh, by the way, how was it? Was it really good?
おー！
Oh—!
ありがとうございます。ちょっとあの、初お披露目だったんで、緊張しながらだったんですが...
Thank you. I was a bit nervous since it was the first performance, but...
ということで、今回もバンドメンバーさんがいます！バンドさーん！
And so, we have band members with us this time too! Band members!
セカンドに引き続きのメンバーでございます。
They're the same members from the second live.
いっしょ、ね、セカンドからいっしょだったよね、みんな、ね？
Same, right? We've been together since the second live, right everyone?
あー、反応してくれてるー。
Ah, you're all reacting!
そして、配信もあります。
Also, there's a livestream.
「推しカメラ」にアピール、はい。
Appealing to the "Oshi-camera" now.
パチコン！
Wink!
可愛いでしょ？
I'm cute, right?
なんと韓国でのライブビューイングも行っているそうです。
Actually, there's even a live viewing in Korea!
アンニョンハセヨ〜！
Annyeonghaseyo!
みんなも、みんなも！はい、アンニョンハセヨ！
Everyone too! Ready? Annyeonghaseyo!
バッチリ！
Perfect!
今回のライブの感想は、ハッシュタグ...
For your thoughts on this concert, use the hashtag...
#駆け抜ける星街 で...
#SpectraOfNova...
たくさんポストして... ポスト...
and post lots of... post...
ツイートしてください！
Please tweet about it!
YouTube、TikTokでご覧の方はここまでとなります。
To those watching on YouTube and TikTok, this is the end of the stream.
そうそう、それそれ。
Right, exactly.
まだまだね、一緒に盛り上がりたいみんなは...
Everyone who wants to keep getting hyped together...
概要欄から配信サイトへ飛んで...
head to the streaming site from the description...
チケットを買ってください！お願いします！
and please buy a ticket! Thank you!
では、そろそろ次の曲が聴きたいですよね？
Now then, you're ready for the next song, right?
そうですよね！
I thought so!
なんと今回ね...
Actually, for this tour...
各地でそれぞれ違うセットリストを用意してるんです。
we've prepared different setlists for each venue.
さあ、埼玉は次どの曲が来るのか。
Now, which song will be next for Saitama?
お楽しみに！
Look forward to it!
無料パートは終了いたしました
The sneak peek part of the show has ended.
ご視聴ありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching!
無料パートは終了いたしました
ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended.
Thank you for watching!